My name is Mike Lewis with Christian Martial Arts.
We are talking about how to throw Ninja Stars.
There are several different styles and different ways to throw Ninja Stars.
There is also many different styles of Ninja Stars themselves.
As you can see here I have one that has four points on it and one here that actually has five points on it.
This one is shaped more like a star.
But you will find some that have three, four, points.
They have different weights, different thicknesses, all that kind of stuff so when you buy Ninja Stars, take a look at them and make sure you are not getting ripped off by buying some really cheap ones and metal ones that will bend after a few throws, get some kinds that are going to be very sturdy when you throw them because they will bend depending on how hard you throw.
Also the style of the Ninja Star sort of depends on how much spin you put on it to make it stick so that is something that when you buy a Ninja Star go out and sort of experiment with it and get a good feel of it and you may have to put more force behind your spin or vice versa, more spin than force.
The first way to start out throwing a Ninja Star, one of the basic ways is to just grab near the tip and I like to turn mine slightly back to help get some spin on to it and so when I throw it I sort of side arm it, throw it, release, and try to put as much spin on the star as I execute.
Pretty much the mindset is like you are trying to crack a whip or a towel and you take and get it there and you have got to first snap it back just a tad bit to get it to pop.
So that is what you are doing, you are taking your Ninja Star and when you try to actually crack the whip per say you are actually spinning your Ninja Star through so that will actually have enough torque and enough force to stick them to your target.
The same thing with this one.
You pretty much just tilt it back.
A lot of people have great aim going around this way but they are able to get a better spin tossing it just like a frisbee.
So you have to find what is best for you.
Same thing, you grab it by the tip, you hold it to your side, you just let it out just like you would a frisbee and when you get your arm executed fully out you just want to sort of snap it out.
You don't want to let your arm pass too far because then your release will be off and you will throw the Ninja Star off so you want to make sure that your arm is locked out to wherever you are throwing your Ninja Star at.
That is just a little bit more information about Ninja Stars and how to get started in throwing.